[Music Playing]
[旁白]  在一个月朗星稀的夜晚
[NARRATOR] On the clearest of nights
伊塞林的晚风缓缓的吹着
when the winds of the Etherium were calm and peaceful.
[Ship Creaking]
一艘巨大的商船
The great merchant ships
满载着来自于大角星的水晶
with their cargoes of Arcturian solar crystals
安全平静地在宇宙中航行着
felt safe and secure.
他们怎么也不会想到自己已经
Little did they suspect that they were pursued by
被海盗盯上了
pirates.
这些海盗中最可怕就是
And the most feared of all these pirates
声名狼藉的船长  纳撒尼尔·弗林特
was the notorious Captain Nathaniel Flint.
开火！
Fire!
[All Gasping]
Aah!
就像一只老鹰在玩弄它的猎物...
Like a Candarian zaftwing overtaking its prey...
[莎拉]  詹姆斯·普莱迪斯·霍金斯
[SARAH] James Pleiades Hawkins.
我以为你一个小时之前就睡着了
I thought you were asleep an hour ago.
妈妈  我刚看到最精彩的部分
Mom, I was just getting to the best part.
让我看吧?
Please?
真拿你没办法
Oh! Can those eyes get any bigger?
坐过去点
Scootch over.
[旁白]  ...就像一只老鹰在玩弄它的猎物
[NARRATOR] ...like a Candarian zaftwing overtaking its prey
弗林特和他的叛军从天而降
Flint and his band of renegades swooped in out of nowhere.
[Jingling]
哈哈哈哈！
Ha ha ha ha!
之后  卷着他们抢来的财宝
And then, gathering up their spoils
消失得无影无踪
vanished without a trace.
- Ooh! - Ooh!
[旁白]  弗林特的秘密宝藏从来没有被人发现过
[NARRATOR] Flint's secret trove was never found.
但是仍然有传说这些宝藏藏在
But stories have persisted that it remains hidden
遥远的银河系的某个地方
somewhere at the farthest reaches of the galaxy.
装载着超乎想象的财宝
Stowed with riches beyond imagination
从成上千个星球上掠夺而来的财宝
The loot of a thousand worlds.
那就是：星银岛
[Jim and NARRATOR] Treasure Planet.
好啦  擤擤你的鼻子
Okay. Blow your nose.
[Honking]
妈妈  你觉得弗林特船长是怎么做到的?
How do you think Captain Flint did it, Mom?
他是怎么突然出现  又消失的无影无踪的呢?
How'd he swoop in out of nowhere and vanished without a trace?
我不知道
I have no idea.
过来  你这个小...
Come here, you...
我要吹了--噢！
I'm gonna get... [Blowing Raspberry]
[Pffft]
[Giggling]
好啦  现在该是小太空人睡觉的时间了
Okay, now it's time for this little spacer to go to sleep.
你觉得会有人找到星银岛吗
You think somebody'll ever find Treasure Planet?
宝贝  我认为这
Sweetheart, I think it's more
更像是一个传说
like a legend.
我知道这是真的
I know it's real.
好吧  这是真的
You win. It's real.
-晚安妈妈  -晚安宝贝
- Nighty-night, Mom. - Nighty-night, sweetheart.
我爱你
I love you.
我也爱你
Love you, too.
[Rustling]
夜晚  伊塞林的晚风
[NARRATOR] There are nights when the winds of the Etherium,
像是邀请别人和它们一起自由飞翔
so inviting in their promise of flight and freedom,
这使人的情绪高涨！
made one's spirit soar!
[Buzzing]
Yaaaa-hoo!
[Alarm Rings]
Whoo!
来吧！
Come on!
Whoo! Ha ha ha!
Whoo-hoo!
[Sirens blaring]
噢！这下可好！
Oh, great.
[Thunder Rumbling]
霍金斯夫人
Mrs. Hawkins!
我知道  果汁续杯
I know, refill on the purpjuice.
马上就来  敦莱蒂夫人
Coming right up, Mrs. Dunwiddie.
上菜了  这是你们点的四份面粉球...
There we go. That's four powdered spheroids...
两份月食  还有这一大碗...
two lunar eclipses, and it's a big bowl...
泽勒林果冻虫  给这个大男孩的
of Zorellian jelly worms for the big boy!
-太棒了！-慢用
- Awesome! - Enjoy.
对不起  德尔波特  今天早上这里闹哄哄的
Sorry, Delbert. It's been a madhouse here all morning.
没事  莎拉
No problem, Sarah.
啊！我的太阳种子杂烩
Ah! My Alponian chowder with the extra solara seed.
嗯！真美味！
Mmm! Yum!
[Sniffing]
你好
Hello.
谁带你来的?
What brings you here？
好奇的小家伙?
Curious little one?
走吧
Go away.
你父母在这吗?
Are your parents around?
怎么回事?猫把你的--呀！
What's the matter? Cat got your... Aah!
[Gulping]
噢  这个年纪的孩子真可爱
Oh, they're so adorable at that age.
噢  是的...糟糕的[口误]
Oh, yes, deplorable...
呃...可爱的！嗯
Uh... Adorable! Hmm.
说起孩子  吉姆最近怎么样
Speaking of which, how's Jim doing?
好多了  我知道他今年初...
Much better. I know he had some rough spots...
遇到一点挫折  但是我现在认为...
earlier this year, but I really think...
他真的开始有转机了
that he's starting to turn a corner.
霍金斯夫人
Mrs. Hawkins?
吉姆！
Jim! [Dishes Clatter]
噢  看来还没完
Ooh... Wrong turn.
好了  谢谢你们送我回来
Okay. Thanks for the lift, guys.
别急
Not so fast.
我们发现你儿子...
We apprehended your son operating...
在限制区域驾驶太阳能交通工具
a solar vehicle in a restricted area.
这行为违反了9-0-4号法律...
Moving violation 9-0-4...
第十五章  嗯...第...
section 15, paragraph, um...
第六段?
Six?
-谢谢  -不客气
- Thank you. - Don't mention it.
-吉姆  -如您所知  夫人...
- Jim! - As you are aware, ma'am...
这是他缓刑期间的一次违反法律
This constitutes a violation of his probation.
是的、是的不  我理解嗯  我们能不能就--
Yes, yes. No, I understand. Um... But could we just...
嗯  打扰一下
DOPPLER: Um, ahem, pardon me.
警官  请允许我  呃  插一句话
Officers, if I might, uh, interject here.
我是著名的天体物理学家  德尔波特·多普勒博士
I am the noted astrophysicist Dr. Delbert Doppler.
你们应该听说过我
Perhaps you've heard of me.
没听说过?呃  我这里有一篇剪报
No? I have a clipping.
-你是这男孩的父亲?  -噢！天哪  不是！
- Are you the boy's father? - Good heavens, no!
他只是我们家的老朋友
Ewww! He's just an old friend of the family.
后退  先生！
Back off, sir!
谢谢你  德尔波特  我会解决的
Thank you, Delbert. I will take it from here.
好的  莎拉  如果你坚持这样
Well, Sarah, if you insist.
以后别再让我干这事儿了
Ahem. Don't ever let me do that again.
由于违反了15-C号条例...
Due to repeated violations of statute 15-C...
我们没收了他的飞行器  如果再犯
we have impounded his vehicle. Any more slip-ups will result
我们定会将他送进少管所
in a one-way ticket to Juvenile Hall.
-少年拘留所  -监狱
- Kiddie hoosegow. - The slammo.
谢谢长官  以后不会再发生了
Thank you, Officers. It won't happen again.
这样的孩子我们见的多了
We see his type all the time, ma'am.
-选择错误  -误入歧途
- Wrong choices. - Dead-enders.
失败者
Losers.
-好自为之  -我们走
- You take care now. - Let's motor.
[Conversations Resume]
吉姆  我已经受够了
Jim, I have had it.
你真的想去少管所  是不是?
Do you want to go to Juvenile Hall? Is that it?
吉姆
Jim?
吉姆  看着我
Jim, look at me.
我辛辛苦苦维持这个旅馆...
It's been hard enough keeping this place...
全都要靠我一个人--
afloat by myself without you going...
妈妈  没什么大不了的  那周围没有别的人
Mom, it's no big deal. There was nobody around.
那些条子总是想...
Those cops just won't get off my...
算了
Forget it.
霍金斯夫人  我的果汁
Mrs. Hawkins! My juice!
好的  马上就来  敦莱蒂夫人
Yes, I'll be right there, Mrs. Dunwiddie.
吉姆  我只是不想看到你...
Jim, I just don't want to see you
放弃你自己的将来
throw away your entire future.
将来?什么将来
Yeah, what future?
[Thunder Rumbling]
[Clang]
真不知道你是怎么过来的  莎拉
[DR DOPPLER] I really don't know how you manage it, Sarah.
一边要经营旅店一边还要抚养...
Trying to run a business while raising a felon like...
像吉姆这样的孩子
Felon... Fellow... Fellow like Jim.
怎么过来的?我已经穷途末路了
Managing it? I'm at the end of my rope.
自从他父亲走后
Ever since his father left,
吉姆从来就没有从中恢复过来
well, Jim's just never recovered.
你知道他是多么的聪明
And you know how smart he is.
他八岁的时候就造了第一个太阳能滑板！
He built his first solar surfer when he was eight!
但是  他没有完成学业
And yet, he's failing at school,
他不断地惹麻烦...
He is constantly in trouble...
跟他说话的时候  他就像个陌生人
and when I talk to him, he's like a stranger to me.
真的不知道怎么办  德尔波特  我已经尽力了
I don't know, Delbert. I've tried everything.
[Engines Sputtering]
嗨  先生?
Hey, Mister?
先生  你没事吧?
Mister, you're okay in there, right?
[Growling] - Aah!
[Coughing]
他就要来了
He's a-comin'.
你能听到他吗?
Can you hear him?
那齿轮和陀螺仪在嘀嗒地转着...
Those gears and gyros clickin' and whirrin'...
就像是魔鬼本身！
like the devil himself!
呃  看来你头撞得不轻
Uh, hit your head there pretty hard, didn't ya?
他在找我的箱子
He's after me chest.
那恶魔般的半机械人  还有他的杀人团伙
That fiendish cyborg and his band of cutthroats.
[Straining]
但是他们必须...
But they'll have to pry it...
先从比利·鲍恩斯冰冷的  死人的手指中探察
from old Billy Bones' cold, dead fingers afore I... Argh!
[Coughing]
噢  天哪--
Oh, my...
呃  来吧  把胳膊给我
Come on, give me your arm.
对了
That's it.
-好孩子  -我这么做妈妈会很高兴的
- Good lad. - Mom's gonna love this.
[Click]
谢谢你听我唠叨  德尔波特
Thanks for listening, Delbert.
我好多了
[Sighs] It helps.
一切都会变好的
It's going to be okay.
放心吧
You'll see.
我一直希望  有一天我打开门...
I keep dreaming one day I'll open that door,
他会像以前一样
and there he'll be, just the way he was.
一个充满欢笑的小男孩  抱着一只新宠物
A smiling, happy little boy, holding a new pet
求我让他收养它
and begging me to let him keep it.
[Thunder]
詹姆斯·普莱迪斯·霍金斯！
[Gasps] James Pleiades Hawkins!
妈妈  他受伤了  伤得很重！
Mom, he's hurt bad!
我的箱子  小伙子
Me chest, lad.
[Gasping]
他马上就来了
[Billy Bones] He'll be comin' soon.
不能让他找到这个
Can't let them find this.
谁要来?
Who's coming?
那个半机械人！
[Whispering] The cyborg!
小心那个半机械人！
Beware the cyborg! [Gasps]
噢！
Ohh!
[Rumbling]
[Sarah Gasps]
快！我们得离开这里！
Quick! We gotta go!
- Ohh! - Aah!
在这件事上我同意吉姆！
I believe I'm with Jim on this one!
[Pirates Shouting]
黛利拉[原是圣经中人物  哈利路亚
Delilah! Hallelujah!
[Yelping Excitedly]
呆在那！别动！
Stay! Don't move!
它在哪里?
[PIRATE] Where is it?
快去找！
Find it!
别担心  莎拉
[DOPPLER] Don't worry, Sarah
我是物理学专家
I'm an expert in the laws of physical science.
-当我数到三就跳下去  -一...三！
- On the count of three. One... - Three!
- Aah! - Aah!
快跑  黛利拉  快跑！
Go, Delilah! Go!
快跑！就是这样！快跑！
Go! That's it! That's it! Go!
驾！驾！
Hyah! Hyah!
[Crickets chirping]
我问过警察了
[DOPPLER] I just spoke with the constabulary.
那些海盗逃走的时候  没有留下任何线索
Those blaggard pirates have fled without a trace.
我很抱歉  莎拉
I'm sorry, Sarah.
恐怕老本鲍旅馆已经被烧成灰烬了
I'm afraid the old Benbow Inn has burned to the ground.
毫无疑问  这一大堆麻烦...
Ahem. Well, certainly a lot of trouble...
都是由那个小球引起的
over that odd little sphere.
那些标记我看不太懂
Those markings baffle me.
我从没见过这样的东西
Unlike anything I've ever encountered.
[Beeps,whirring]
即使以我的丰富的经验...
Even with my vast experience...
和惊人的智慧
and superior intellect
都得花好几年才能打开它  --嘿！
it would take me years to unlock its... Hey!
[Gasps]
什么  是张地图
Why, it's a map!
等等  等等
Wait. Wait, wait, wait!
我们在这里  特雷斯普行星
This is us, the planet Montressor.
[Gasps]
那是麦哲伦星云！
That's the Magellanic Cloud!
喔！珊瑚星系！
Whoo! The Coral Galaxy!
那是天鹅座十字星
That's the Cygnus Cross,
克里安黑洞
And that's the Kerian Abyss.
等等  这是什么  这是什么?  奇怪  它是...
Wait. What's this? What's this? Why, it... It's...
星银岛
Treasure Planet.
不会吧！
No!
是星银岛！
That's Treasure Planet!
弗林特的宝藏?
Flint's trove?
掠夺上千个世界的战利品
The loot of a thousand worlds?
你知道这意味着什么吗?
You know what this means?
就是说所有的财宝仅仅一船之遥
It means that all that treasure is only a boat ride away.
无论谁去将它取回将终身享用不尽...
Whoever brings it back would hold an eternal place...
比发现万神殿的探险者还要伟大！他会有可能体验到--
atop the pantheon of explorers! He'd be able to experience...
喔！发生了什么了?
[Click] - Whoo! What just happened?
妈妈  就是它了  这将是解决我们所有的问题的办法
Mom, this is it. This is the answer to all our problems.
吉姆  这绝对不可能--
Jim, there is absolutely no way...
难道你不记得了  所有那些故事?
Don't you remember, all those stories?
那些只不过是--传说！
That's all they were. Stories!
拥有了那些财宝...
With that treasure...
我们可以建造数百个本鲍旅馆
we could rebuild the Benbow a hundred times over!
好吧  这是--这只不过是--噢  天哪
Well, this is... lt's just... Oh, my.
德尔波特  你能解释一下这有多荒唐吗?
Delbert, would you please explain how ridiculous this is?
真是太荒谬了...
It's totally preposterous...
你不能独自一个人穿越整个星系
traversing the entire galaxy alone.
终于我们能听到些理智的话了
Now, at last, we hear some sense!
-所以我要和你一起去  -德尔波特
- That's why I'm going with you. - Delbert!
我要用我的积蓄来支持这次探险
I'll use my savings to finance the expedition.
我要租用一艘船  雇佣一个船长和一队船员
I'll commission a ship, hire a captain and a crew.
你不是认真的吧
You're not serious.
我一生都在等待这样的机会...终于来了
All my life I've been waiting for an opportunity like this...
它在呼唤我：快去吧！戴尔波特  快去吧！
and here it is screaming, "Go, Delbert! Go, Delbert!"
好吧  好吧！你们俩都被禁足了！
Okay. Okay! You're both grounded!
[Sighs]
妈妈  听着
[JIM] Mom, look.
我知道我总是惹麻烦
I know that I keep messing everything up
我也知道...
and I know...
我让你很失望
that I let you down.
但这是我向你证明我自己的机会
But this is my chance to make it up to you.
我会把一切处理的妥妥当当的
I'm gonna set things right.
莎拉
Sarah?
能过来一下吗?
If I may?
你自己说过  你什么方法都试过了
You said yourself, you've tried everything.
就让他到太空里去磨练几个月
There are much worse remedies
也许是个好办法
than a few character-building months in space.
你这么说是因为  这样能帮到他...
Are you saying this because it's the right thing...
还是因为你真的想去
or because you really want to go?
我真的  真的  真的  真的很想去...
I really, really, really, really want to go...
而且也能帮到他
and it's the right thing.
[Sighs]
吉姆
Jim.
我不想失去你
I don't want to lose you.
妈妈...不会的
Mom, you won't.
我会让你感到自豪
I'll make you proud.
好吧  呃...
[DOPPLER] Well, uh, ahem...
那就这样了
There we are then.
我们马上就开始准备
We'll begin preparations at once.
吉姆  我的孩子  那我们立刻就动身去太空港
Jim, my boy, soon we'll be off to the spaceport.
[Whoosh]
[Squawking]
[Creatures speaking alien languages]
吉姆！  噢！  吉姆！等等我！
[DOPPLER] Jim! Oh, Jim! Wait for me!
[Clanking]
[Breathing deeply]
呃  吉姆  我们应该趁这个机会
Well, Jim, this should be a wonderful opportunity
好好相互了解一下
for the two of us to get to know one another.
就像他们说的什么  亲情沟通  呃...
You know what they say, familiarity breeds, um...
好吧  你不在乎  但是对我们来说...
well, contempt, but in our case...
听着  我们还是先找到我们的船吧  好吗?
Look, let's just find the ship. Okay?
[Clank]
-右手边第二个码头  -你可以找到的
- Second berth on your right! - You can't miss it.
嗨  谢了
Hey, thanks.
是因为这身行头对吗  我就不应该听...
It's the suit, isn't it? I should never have listened...
那个双头女商人的推销
to that pushy two-headed saleswoman.
一个头说大小正合适  另一个头说这颜色适合我
This one said it fit, that one said it was my color.
我都不知该怎么办了  我被搞糊涂了  噢！
I didn't know what to do. I get so flustered. Ooh!
噢  吉姆！这是我们的船！R.L.S. Legacy！
Oh, Jim! This is our ship! The R.L.S. Legacy!
Whoa!
把这些桶装到前面去！
[OFFICER] Stow those casks forward!
装上去！
Heave together now!
太酷了！
How cool is this?
[Squishing noise]
对不起  我不是故意的--
- Sorry about that. I didn't mean... [Angry farting noises]
让我来搞定他
Allow me to handle this.
[Blowing Raspberries]
[Squeaking]
[Happy Fart Noises]
我的弗拉图拉语很流利  吉姆
I'm fluent in Flatula, Jim.
我中学的时候学过两年
Took two years of it in high school. [Blows]
弗拉图拉语  酷！
Flatula? Cool.
早上好  船长  一切都井然有序吗?
Good morning, Captain. Everything shipshape?
一切都很好  先生 但我不是船长
Shipshape it is, sir, but I'm not the captain.
船长在上面
The captain's aloft.
[Meows]
埃柔先生  这艘船我已经检查过了...
Mr. Arrow, I've checked this miserable ship...
每一处细节都和往常一样...井井有条
from stem to stern and, as usual, it's spot on.
你从来不犯错的吗?
Can you get nothing wrong?
您过奖了  船长
You flatter me, Captain.
啊  我想你就是多普勒博士吧?
Ah. Dr. Doppler, I presume?
呃  是的  我...
Uh, um... Yes. I...
-你好啊  听得见吗?  -别敲了  我听得听见！
- Hello! Can you hear me? - Yes, I can! Stop that banging!
让我来帮你  博士  这个要这样...
If I may, Doctor, this works so much better...
-然后再插上插头  -噢！
when it's right-way up and plugged in. - Ooh!
好了  正常了
Lovely. There you go.
您要是不介意  我自己可以插
If you don't mind, I can manage my own plugging!
我是阿米莉娅船长...
I'm Captain Amelia...
不久前跟普洛腾舰队有点儿小冲突
late of a few run-ins with the Protean Armada.
不太愉快  我就不说了
Nasty business, but I won't bore you with my scars.
这是我的大副  埃柔先生
You've met my first officer, Mr. Arrow.
淳朴  强壮  可靠  诚实  勇猛  忠实
Sterling, tough, dependable, honest, brave, and true.
行了  船长
Please, Captain.
哦  闭嘴  埃柔  我只是说说而已
Shut up, Arrow. You know I don't mean a word of it.
呃  请原谅我不想打断这有趣的玩笑...
Ahem. Excuse me. I hate to interrupt this lovely banter...
但是  我要向你们介绍  吉姆·霍金斯
but may I introduce to you Jim Hawkins.
吉姆  你知道  就是找到藏宝图的...
Jim, you see, is the boy who found the treasure...
博士  够了！
Doctor, please!
[Growls]
到我的船舱去谈吧
I'd like a word with you in my stateroom.
博士  你刚刚在那些船员面前
Doctor, to muse and blabber about a treasure map
高谈阔论关于藏宝图的事
in front of this particular crew
在我看来真是一种近乎低能的行为
Demonstrates a level of ineptitude that borders on the imbecilic.
我这么说已经很客气了
And I mean that in a very caring way.
你说我低能?愚蠢  我...
"Imbecilic," did you say? Foolishness, I've...
我能先看看藏宝图吗?
May I see the map, please?
接着
Here.
Hmm.
有意思
Fascinating.
霍金斯先生  以后...
Mr. Hawkins, in the future...
你的称呼我"舰长"或"长官"
you will address me as "Captain" or "ma'am."
清楚了吗?
Is that clear?
Ugh...
霍金斯先生?
Mr. Hawkins?
-是  长官  -就是这样
- Yes, ma'am. - That'll do.
先生们  藏宝图不用的时候必须锁好
Gentlemen, this must be kept under lock and key when not in use.
还有  博士  再一次好心的提醒你
And, Doctor, again, with the greatest possible respect
闭上你的嘴
Zip your howling screamer.
舰长  我向你保证...
Captain, I assure you I...
我长话短说
Let me make this as monosyllabic as possible.
我一点也不喜欢你雇来的那些船员
I don't much care for this crew you hired.
他们...我怎么形容他们来着?  埃柔
They're... How did I describe them, Arrow?
我早上喝咖啡的时候说过句绝的
I said something rather good this morning before coffee.
"一堆滑稽的流着口水的傻子"长官
"A ludicrous parcel of driveling galoots," ma'am.
-就是这样  很贴切  -你给我听好...
- There you go. Poetry. - Now, see here...
博士  我也很想和你聊天、喝茶、吃蛋糕  那该有多好
Doctor, I'd love to chat, tea, cake, the whole shebang.
但我还得准备起航
But I have a ship to launch.
你也得准备你的装备
And you've got your outfit to buff up.
埃柔先生  请把这两个菜鸟带到厨房去
Mr. Arrow, please escort these two neophytes down to the galley straightaway.
年轻的霍金斯就跟着  我们的厨子席尔瓦先生一起干活
Young Hawkins will be working for our cook, Mr. Silver.
什么?厨子?
What? The cook?
那个女人！那只...猫！
That woman! That feline!
她搞清楚谁才是头儿了没有
Who does she think is working for whom?
藏宝图是我的  她居然叫我打杂?
It's my map, and she's got me bussin' tables?
我不允许你们对船长有任何不敬！
I'll not tolerate a cross word about our captain!
在任何星系都不可能找比她更好的长官了
There's no finer officer in this or any galaxy.
[Whistling]
席尔瓦先生
Mr. Silver?
啊  埃柔先生
Why, Mr. Arrow, sir.
您这样的绅士能来我的厨房  我真的太荣幸了
Bringin' in such fine and distinguished gents to grace my humble galley.
早知道  我就先收拾一下了
Had I known, I'd have tucked in me shirt.
呵呵呵呵！
Heh heh heh heh!
一个半机械人！
A cyborg!
这位是多普勒博士
May I introduce Dr. Doppler,
我们这次航行的资助者
the financier of our voyage.
装备不错呀  博士
Love the outfit, Doc.
谢谢  呃...你的眼睛也不错
Well, thank you. Um, love the eye.
这小伙子是吉姆·霍金斯
Uh, this young lad is Jim Hawkins.
吉姆！哦...
Jimbo! Uh...
别被这一大堆金属工具吓到了
Now, don't be too put off by this hunk of hardware.
[Humming]
Whoa!
适应这些工具需要些时间
These gears have been tough getting used to.
可是用起来还挺顺手的
But they do come in mighty handy from time to time.
Mmm!
好了  来  尝尝我最拿手的炖骨兽肉
Here, now, have a taste of me famous bonzabeast stew.
[Sniffing]
呣  香气扑鼻  让人感觉精力充沛
Mmm! Delightfully tangy, yet robust.
祖传秘方
Old family recipe.
Aah!
实际上  这也是老祖宗传下来的
In fact, that was part of the old family!
开个玩笑  博士
I'm just kiddin', Doc!
嗯  好吧
Yeah, well...
不开玩笑就不是我了
I'm nothin' if I ain't a kidder.
来吧  吉姆  来一大口
Go on, Jimbo. Have a swig.
[Giggling]
墨菲！
Morph!
你这个摇头晃脑的调皮鬼！
You jiggle-headed blob of mischief!
原来你藏在那！
So that's where you was hiding!
[Chattering]
[Belch]
那是什么东西?
What is that thing?
"那是什么东西?"
"What is that thing?"
他是个变形怪
He's a morph.
我在海神星1号上救了这个小变形怪
I rescued the little shape-shifter on Proteus 1.
[Cooing]
嗷  他非常喜欢我
Aw, he took a shine to me.
从那以后我们就在一起了
We been together ever since.
是吗?乖孩子
Right? Yeah. Nice boy.
我们就要起航了
We're about to get underway.
你想看看起航吗  博士?
Would you like to observe the launch, Doctor?
当然！
Would I?
现在的星系核有超光速喷流吗?
Does an active galactic nucleus have superluminal jets?
我跟你去
I'll follow you.
席尔瓦先生  霍金斯先生留在这里听你的指示
Mr. Hawkins will stay here in your charge, Mr. Silver.
[Cough]
抱歉  先生  但是...
Beggin' your pardon, sir, but...
这是舰长的命令！别让这孩子偷懒
Captain's orders! See to it the new cabin boy's kept busy.
-但是...  -不  你不能...
- But, no, but... - No, you can't...
[Both Sigh]
好吧  船长让你跟着我  是吗?
So, Captain's put you with me, eh?
随便了
Whatever.
我这个卑下的半机械人怎么敢抗命不尊呢?
Well, who be a humble cyborg to argue with a captain?
是吧
Yeah.
知道吗  这些紫色的蔬菜...
You know, these purps...
和蒙特里莎星球上生长的蔬菜很像
they're kind of like the ones back home on Montressor.
你去过那儿吗?
You ever been there?
我好像没去过那  吉姆
I can't say as I have, Jimbo.
我还记得  在我来这之前...
Come to think of it, just before I left...
碰到过一个老头  他...
I met this old guy who was, um...
在找他的一个朋友  也是半机械人
He was kind of looking for a cyborg buddy of his.
是吗?
Is that so?
没错
Yeah.
那老头叫什么名字来着？
What was that old salamander's name?
对了  叫鲍恩斯
Oh, yeah. Bones.
比利·鲍恩斯
Billy Bones?
鲍恩斯？鲍恩斯？
Bones? Bones?
我没什么印象
T'ain't ringin' any bells.
可能是另一个半机械人
Must have been a different cyborg.
这个港口有很多像我这样的半机械人
There's a slew of cyborgs roamin' this port.
准备起锚！
[Whistle on deck] Prepare to cast off!
去吧  小伙子  看看船起航
Off with you, lad, and watch the launch.
回头还有很多活等着你干呢
There'll be plenty work a-waitin' for you afterwards.
[Humming] [Chattering]
我们最好盯紧点这个家伙  是不是  墨菲
We best be keepin' a sharp eye on this one, eh, Morph?
让他别惹那些他不该惹的闲事
We wouldn't want him strayin' into things he shouldn't.
都准备好了  舰长！
We're all clear, Captain!
好了  我的朋友  让这艘破船升空吧
Well, my friend. Are we ready to raise this creaking tub?
遵命  舰长
My pleasure, Captain.
全体船员就位！
All hands to stations!
机灵点儿！
Smartly now!
快点  你这个下贱渣滓！  我要追上你！
Come on, you scurvy scum! I'll race you!
展开所有太阳帆！
Loose all solar sails!
[Grunting]
加把劲！
Come on!
拉起吊带
Heave up the braces.
拉紧
Brace up.
Ooh! Oh!
佐夫先生  开启人造重力
Mr. Zoff, engage artificial gravity.
[Farting]
[Clanking]
[Clattering]
腾巴克先生  南偏西  转向  2-1-0-0
South by southwest, Mr. Turnbuckle, heading 2-1-0-0.
是  船长  2-1-0-0
Aye, Captain. 2-1 -0-0.
全速前进  埃柔先生
Full speed, Mr. Arrow, if you please.
全速前进！
Take her away!
站稳了  博士
Brace yourself, Doctor.
Aah! Oof!
Whoa.
[Calling]
难以置信  奥克斯星系鱼！
Upon my word, an Orcus Galacticus.
笑一个
Smile.
博士  要是我会站远...
Doctor, I'd stand clear...
啊  真是个航行的好日子  舰长
'Tis a grand day for sailing, Captain,
看看你
And look at you.
就像一艘上了新帆  涂了新漆的帆船一样  英姿焕发！
You're as trim and as bonny as a sloop with new sails and a fresh coat of paint.
那些甜言蜜语  还是留着给那些太空港的妓女说吧
You can keep that kind of flim-flammery for your spaceport floozies, Silver.
"太空妓女  太空妓女..."
"Spaceport floozy, spaceport floozy..."
你太伤我的心了  舰长
You cut me to the quick, Captain.
我一直都是怎么想就怎么说的
I speaks nothing but me heart at all times.
"怎么想就怎么说"
MORPH: "Nothing but me heart."
顺便提一句  在横桅索上无所事事的菜鸟...
And, by the way, isn't that your cabin boy...
不是应该归你管的吗？
aimlessly footling about in those shrouds?
Yep, it...
我一时疏忽了舰长  我这就处理  吉姆！
A momentary aberration, Cap'n, soon to be addressed. Jimbo!
我有两个新朋友  你们来认识一下
I got two new friends I'd like you to meet.
跟拖把先生和水桶女士问个好吧
Say hello to Mr. Mop and Mrs. Bucket.
Heh heh heh heh!
Yippie.
开始拖地吧  拖把先生
Yeah, I got your Mr. Mop.
小心点  蠢货！
Watch it, twerp.
[Murmuring]
你看什么看  怪物？
What are you looking at, weirdo?
就是  怪物
Yeah, weirdo.
[Hisssss]
小伙子  你要学会少管闲事
Cabin boys should learn to mind their own business.
怎么  你有不可告人的秘密吗？大眼睛？
Why? You got something to hide, bright eyes?
看来你的耳朵不太好使
Maybe your ears don't work so well.
[Grunts] Yeah. Ahem.
不幸的是  我的鼻子太好使了
Too bad my nose works just fine.
你这个放肆的小...
Why, you impudent little...
[Crew shouting]
动手！把他撕成碎片！
Go ahead! Slice him! Dice him! [FARTING NOISE]
有什么遗言吗  伙计？
Any last words, cabin boy?
斯科洛先生
Mr. Scroop
你知道用力捏一个...
You ever see what happens to a fresh purp...
新鲜紫薯会发生什么吗？
when you squeeze real hard?
出什么事了
What's all this, then?
你们知道规矩
You know the rules.
不准在这艘船上滋事
There'll be no brawling on this ship.
是  长官
Aye-aye, sir.
谁要是再犯的话  就得被关在禁闭室里...
Any further offenders will be confined to the brig...
直到这趟旅程结束
for the remainder of the voyage.
清楚了吗  斯科洛先生
Am I clear, Mr. Scroop?
非常清楚
Transparently.
干得好  埃柔先生
Well done, Mr. Arrow, sir!
纪律严明的船队才是好船队  长官
A tight ship's a happy ship, sir.
吉姆  我已经给过你活干了
Jimbo, I gave you a job.
我一直都在干活  是那个臭虫子...
Hey, I was doing it until that bug thing...
给我闭嘴！我要你把甲板擦得干干净净...
Belay that! Now, I want this deck swabbed spotless...
我回来之前还没做好  你可别怪我
and heaven help you if I come back and it's not done.
墨菲  给我盯着这个小子
Morph? Keep an eye on this pup.
要是他还偷懒  就过来告诉我
And let me know if there be any more distractions.
Okay. Aye-aye-
[Chattering]
[Sighs]
[Crew grumbling]
好了  大家都到齐了
So, we're all here, then.
-让一下  -很好
- Excuse me. - Fine.
那么  请恕我直言  先生们...
Now, if you pardon my plain speaking, gentlemen...
你们都是...
Are you all...
彻头彻尾  不可救药的蠢货吗
stark-raving, totally blinking daft? [Chatters]
我好不容易让大家以水手的身份上船
After all me finagling getting us hired as an upstanding crew
还没到合适的时机  你们想让计划全部败露吗？
You want to blow the whole mutiny before its time?
那男孩已经有所察觉了
The boy was sniffing about.
你们只需按照计划行事  你们这些愚蠢的虫脑袋
You just stick to the plan, you bug-brained twit.
至于那个小孩  我会给他一堆的活儿...
As for the boy, I'll run him so ragged...
让他没有时间去想
he won't have time to think.
[Morph laughs]
[Coughs]
[Sighs]
这真是有趣的一天
Well, this has been a fun day, huh?
交了新朋友  那个像神经病的蜘蛛
Making new friends, like that spider psycho.
"神经病的蜘蛛  神经病的蜘蛛"
"Spider psycho, spider psycho."
哈  还得再丑一点
Heh. A little uglier.
Mwah-ha-ha-ha!
很像了
Pretty close.
感谢上帝  真是奇迹呀
Well, thank heavens for little miracles.
你拖了一个小时  甲板还是老样子
Up here for an hour, and the deck's still in one piece.
Um...
我...
Look,I...
你为我出头...
What you did...
谢谢你
Thanks.
你爸爸就没有教过你  怎样去避免争斗吗？
Didn't your pop ever teach you to pick your fights a bit more carefully?
你父亲不善于教诲
Your father not the teachin' sort?
不
No.
只是他离家之后就再也没回来
He was more the taking off and never coming back sort.
哦
Oh.
对不起  小伙子
Sorry, lad.
没什么大不了的  我很好
Hey, no big deal. I'm doing just fine.
是吗？
Is that so?
好吧  既然舰长把你交给我管...
Well, since the captain has put you in my charge...
不管你喜不喜欢  我都要...
like it or not, I'll be pounding a few skills...
教你几招  好让你不再惹麻烦
into that thick head of yours to keep you out of trouble.
-什么？  -从现在开始
- What? - From now on,
我会一直盯着你
I'm not letting you out of me sight.
你不能...
You can't do...
就连你吃饭、睡觉、抓屁股都得经过我的同意
You won't so much as eat, sleep, or scratch your bum without my say-so.
我用不着你管！
Don't do me any favors!
你放心好了  小子
You can be sure of that, my lad.
放心好了
You can be sure of that.
Heh heh heh heh!
使点劲儿
Put some elbow into it.
♪ I am a question to the world
♪ Not an answer to be heard
♪ Or a moment that's held in your arms
♪ And what do you think you'd ever say
♪ I won't listen anyway
♪ You don't know me
♪ And I'll never be what you want me to be
♪ And what do you think you'd understand?
♪ I'm a boy, no, I'm a man
♪ You can take me and throw me away
♪ And how can you learn what's never shown
♪ Yeah, you stand here on your own
♪ They don't know me
♪ 'Cause I'm not here
♪ And I want a moment to be real
♪ Want to touch things I don't feel
♪ Want to hold on and feel I belong
♪ And how can the world want me to change
♪ They're the ones that stay the same
♪ They don't know me
♪ But I'm still here
♪ And you see the things they never see
♪ All you wanted I could be
♪ Now you know me
♪ And I'm not afraid
♪ And I want to tell you who I am
♪ Can you help me be a man?
♪ They can't break me
♪ As long as I know who I am
♪ They can't tell me who to be
♪ 'Cause I'm not what they see
♪ Yeah, the world is still sleeping
♪ While I keep on dreaming for me
♪ And the words are just whispers and lies
♪ That I'll never believe
♪ And I want a moment to be real
♪ Want to touch things I don't feel
♪ Want to hold on and feel I belong
Whoa!
♪ How can you say I never change?
♪ They're the ones that stay the same
♪ I'm the one now
♪ 'Cause I'm still here
♪ I'm the one son still here
♪ I'm still here
[Song fades]
[Pulley squeaking]
[Grunting]
你不行了吗?
You having a little trouble there?
离我远点儿
Get away from me.
[Laughing]
哦  吉姆
Oh, Jimbo.
如果我在你这个年纪  能够这么灵活的操纵小艇...
If I could maneuver a skiff like that when I was your age...
我走在大街上  人们一定会向我鞠躬的
they'd be bowing in the streets when I walked by today.
"向我鞠躬"
"Bowing in the streets."
也许吧
I don't know.
我离开家的时候  可没人这么待见我
They weren't exactly singing my praises when I left home.
- Heh. Whew. -"Whew."
可我要改变这一切
But I'm gonna change all that.
是吗?  怎么改变?
Are you now? How so?
Uh...
我有个计划
I got some plans.
会让所有人刮目相看
Gonna make people see me a little different.
Ooh.
有时候  人算不如天算
Sometimes plans go astray.
这一次不会
Not this time.
Hmm.
Ooh...
[Chatters]
噢  谢谢你  墨菲
Oh. Thank you, Morphy.
对了  你怎么会变成这样的?
So, how'd that happen anyway?
为了追逐梦想  得做些牺牲
You give up a few things chasing a dream.
这样值得吗?
Was it worth it?
Heh.
[Sighs]
我希望值得  吉姆
I'm hoping it is, Jimbo.
我一直坚信
I most surely am.
[Screams]
[Ship groans]
搞什么鬼
What the devil?
我的天呐
Good heavens.
那个普鲁沙星球...
The star Pelusa...
它变成超新星了!
it's gone supernova!
腾巴克先生  立刻闪避
Evasive action, Mr. Turnbuckle!
遵命  舰长
Aye-aye, Captain.
所有船员  系紧救生索
All hands, fasten your lifelines!
[Shouting]
埃柔先生  保护好太阳帆!
Mr. Arrow, secure those sails!
保护船帆!
Secure all sails!
把船帆收起来!
Reef them down, men!
吔  宝贝  击中了 哈哈哈哈
Yeah, baby! Ba-boom! Ha ha ha ha!
-啊!  -席尔瓦!
- Aah! - Silver!
谢谢你  孩子
Whoa. Thanks, lad.
[Yelling]
舰长  那颗超新星!
Captain, the star!
演变成了一个...
It's devolving into a... [Gasps]
黑...洞
A black hole!
我们要被吸进去了!  噢!
We're being pulled in! Ohh!
不  休想...
No, you don't, you...
这该死的冲击波!  实在太不规律了!
Blast these waves! They're so deucedly erratic!
不  舰长  它们是可以预测的
No, Captain. They're not erratic at all.
再过47.2秒  还会有下一个冲击波...
There'll be one more in precisely 47.2 seconds...
之后还会有一个最大的!
followed by the biggest magilla of them all!
对了  太好了博士
Of course! Brilliant, Doctor!
我们可以借助最后一波的冲击  离开这里
We'll ride that last magilla out of here.
船帆都收好了  舰长!
All sails secured, Captain!
很好  现在马上展开船帆!
Good man! Now release them immediately!
遵命  舰长  你们都听到了  伙计们
Aye, Captain. You heard her, men.
展开所有船帆
Unfurl those sails.
-什么?  -可我们才刚刚绑好!
- What? - But we just finished...Tying them down!
到底要怎么样  想好了再说!
Make up your blooming minds!
霍金斯先生...
Mr. Hawkins...
检查所有的救生索  务必把他们全都绑好!
make sure all lifelines are secured good and tight!
遵命  舰长!
Aye-aye, Captain.
救生索都系紧了  舰长!
Lifelines secured, Captain!
很好!
Very good!
[Gasps]
Aah!
舰长  最后的冲击波!
Captain, the last wave!
就要来了!
Here it comes!
抓紧你们的救生索!
Hold on to your lifelines, gents!
下面的航行会很颠簸
It's gonna be a bumpy ride!
[Whimpers]
[Boom]
Oof!
[Crew Laughing]
[Cheering]
[Sighs]
舰长  刚才真的是...我的天呐  真是...
Captain! That... Oh, my goodness. That was...
那绝对是...那是最...
That was absolutely... That was the most...
哦  闭嘴吧  事实上  博士...
Oh, tish-tosh. Actually, Doctor...
你的天文学建议确实很有帮助
your astronomical advice was most helpful.
呃...谢谢  谢谢夸奖
Well, uh, uh, thank you. Thank you very much.
我还有很多天闻[口误]...不
Well, I have a lot of help to offer anatomically...
是天稳...天文学的建议
Amanamonically... Astronomically. [Slap]
对了  席尔瓦先生  我该恭喜你
Well, I must congratulate you, Mr. Silver.
那打杂的小子  把救生索固定的非常牢固
It seems your cabin boy did a bang-up job with those lifelines.
[Both chuckle]
大家都平安吧  埃柔先生
All hands accounted for, Mr. Arrow?
埃柔先生?
Mr. Arrow?
很遗憾  埃柔先生已经殉职了
I'm afraid Mr. Arrow has been lost.
他的救生索没有系牢
His lifeline was not secured.
不  我都检查过了
No, I checked them all.
我  我的却都检查过了  全都固定了
I... I did. I checked them all They were secure.
我发誓
I swear.
埃柔先生是一个...
Mr. Arrow was
[Clears Throat]
一个优秀的太空员
A fine spacer
比我们中的许多人  要优秀得多
finer than most of us could ever hope to be,
但他跟我们一样  知道太空航行的风险
But he knew the risks, as do we all.
回到岗位上去  继续前进
Resume your posts. We carry on.
[Whimpers]
这不是你的错
It weren't your fault, you know.
[Sighs]
要不是你的话  一半的人都会被卷进那个黑...
Why, half the crew would be spinning in that black abyss...
听着  你不明白吗?  是我搞砸了!
Look, don't you get it? I screwed up!
有那么一瞬间  我想我可以把事情做好  但是...
For two seconds, I thought that maybe I could do something right, but...
啊!  我只是...
Aagh! I just...
[Sighs]
算了  算了
Just forget it. Forget it.
过来  你听我说  詹姆斯·霍金斯
Now, you listen to me, James Hawkins.
你有着惊人的天赋...
You got the makings of greatness in ya...
不过你要抱紧舵轮  开辟出你自己的航线
but you gotta take the helm and chart your own course.
坚持到底  勇往直前  无畏风暴
Stick to it, no matter the squalls
当时机成熟  当你有机会发挥你的才能...
And when the time comes you get the chance to really test the cut of your sails...
展现你真正实力的时候 我希望我能在场...
and show what you're made of, well, I hope I'm there...
沐浴在你辉煌灿烂的胜利荣耀之中
catching some of the light coming off ya that day.
[Sniffles]
[Sobs softly]
好了  好了
There, there.
小子  没事了  吉姆
Lad, it's all right, Jimbo.
没事了
It's all right.
呃  吉姆  我...
Now, Jim, I...
我得去站岗了
I best be getting about my watch,
你也赶紧去睡一觉吧
and you best be getting some shut-eye.
[Chattering]
我有点儿陷得太深了  墨菲
Getting in too deep here, Morphy.
回头他们又要说我  变得心慈手软了
Next thing ya know, they'll be saying I've gone soft.
[Crew Snoring]
[Muttering]
[Poomp phem poom-poomp]
Uh-oh! Oh! Ugh!
[Sighs]
墨菲?
Morph?
墨菲  别闹了  现在还太早
Morph, knock it off. It's too early for this.
噢  嘿  墨菲!
Ow! Hey, Morph!
Pbbbt!
[Laughs]
-嘿  你给我过来  -"你给我过来"
- Hey, come back here! -"Come back here!"
抓到了!
Gotcha!
[Sighs]
够了  你这个小乌贼
That's it, you little squid.
"小乌贼  小乌贼"
"You little squid. You little squid.
"小乌贼  小乌贼  小乌贼  小乌贼"
"Squid. squid. squid. squid."
[Grunting]
哈!
Ha!
你输了!
Busted!
听着  我们的意思是不想再等了
Look, what we're saying is, we're sick of all this waiting.
他们只剩三个人了
There's only three of them left.
我们想立刻行动
We are wanting to move.
拿到财宝之前  我们不能行动
We don't move till we got the treasure in hand.
我说现在就宰了他们
I say we kill 'em all now.
在这儿我说了算!
I say what's to say!
要是再像害死埃柔那样...
Disobey my orders again...
擅自违抗我的命令
like that stunt you pulled with Mr. Arrow,
你的下场就和他一样!
and so help me, you'll be joining him!
话说得挺狠  但我知道你心里在想什么
Strong talk, but I know otherwise.
你想说什么  斯科洛
You got something to say, Scroop?
那个小子
It's that boy.
我看你好像对他有点心软了
Me thinks you have a soft spot for him.
对啊
Yeah
你们所有人  都给我听好了!
Now, mark me, the lot of ya.
我只关心一件事  那就是...
I care about one thing, and one thing only!
弗林特的宝藏
Flint's trove.
你们认为我会为了一个小子
You think I'd risk it all for the sake
拿宝藏来冒险吗?
of some nose-wiping little whelp?
你怎么说来着?
What was it now?
"你有着惊人的天赋..."
"Oh, you got the makings of greatness in ya."
闭上你的臭嘴!
Shut your yap!
我安慰那个孩子  是为了不让他发现我们的行动
I cozied up to that kid to keep him off our scent.
我是不会心软的
But I ain't gone soft.
看见陆地了!
Land ho!
就在那儿!
There it is!
张大眼睛  一起狂欢吧!
Feast eyes and click heels, if you got 'em.
我的望远镜搁哪了?
Where the devil's me glass?
吉姆
Jimbo.
你在跟我玩游戏  对吗
Playing games, are we?
是啊
Yeah.
我们都在玩游戏
Yeah, we're playing games.
是吗  我向来不太擅长玩游戏
Oh, I see. Well, I was never much good at games
因为我讨厌失败
Always hated to lose. [Click]
Hmm.
-我也一样  -啊!
- Me, too! - Aah!
好吧
Right-O.
该死!
Ohh. Blast it all.
[Blows Whistle]
计划有变  伙计们
Change in plan, lads!
我们现在就行动!
We move now!
[Cheering]
挂上我们的旗  奥讷斯先生
Strike our colors, Mr. Onus.
我的荣幸  舰长
With pleasure, Captain.
[Roars]
我的船上有海盗?  我要看着他们全都被绞死
Pirates on my ship? I'll see they all hang.
博士  会用这个吗?
Doctor, familiar with these?
呃  我看过  在书上读到过...
Oh, I've seen... Well, I've read...
呃  不...我不会用
Uh, no. No. No, I'm not.
Ooh.
霍金斯先生  用你的生命保护它
Mr. Hawkins! Defend this with your life.
墨菲!  给我!
Morph! Give me that!
难道你们要磨蹭一整天吗
You're taking all day about it.
Oh!
截住他们!
Stop them!
Aah, aah, aah. Oof!
谢谢!
Thank you!
到大艇上去  快!
To the longboats, quickly!
Unh
Rrr-yeah!
墨菲  不!
Morph! No!
尝尝这个  你们这些脓包!
Chew on this, you pus-filled boils!
[Screaming]
你是瞄准了打的吗?
Did you actually aim for that?
没错  当然瞄准了
You know, actually, I did.
[Gears turning]
该死!
Oh, blast it.
博士  我说"开枪"你就射断前面的缆绳
Doctor, when I say "now," shoot out the forward cable.
我射后面的
I'll take this one.
墨菲  过来!  墨菲!
Morph, here! Morph!
墨菲!
Morph!
墨菲  到这儿来
Morphy, come here. [WHISTLES]
墨菲  快把它给我  墨菲  过来
Morph. Morph. Bring it here. Morph, come here.
过来  到爸爸这来
Come here. Come here, boy. Come to your dad.
到这儿来  好孩子  墨菲!
Come here, boy. Morph!
-快过来  -墨菲  墨菲  过来!
- Come on! - Morph! Morph, here!
-墨菲!  -墨菲!
Morphy! - Morph!
Ohh.
[Powers Up]
[Beeping]
[Sighs]
开枪!
Now!
Whoa!
[Grunts]
吉姆!
Jim!
参数正常  液压系统启动
Parameters met. Hydraulics engaged.
就这样  到爸爸这儿来吧
That's it! Come to papa!
别开炮!  我们会失去藏宝图的!
Hold your fire! We'll lose the map!
舰长  正上方有激光炮!
Captain! Laser ball at 12 o'clock!
- Whoa! - Aah!
[Creaking]
Ow.
噢  我的天呐!
Oh, my goodness.
太好玩了  我都想再来一次
That was more fun than I ever want to have again.
[Laughing]
这不是我最成功的着陆
That's not one of my gossamer landings.
舰长!
Captain!
Oh. Ooh.
噢  不要大惊小怪
Oh, don't fuss.
Uh... uh...
只是轻微的擦伤而已
Slight bruising. That's all.
喝杯茶就没事了
Cup of tea, and I'll be right as rain.
霍金斯先生
Mr. Hawkins.
请把地图给我
The map, if you please.
Ah.
墨菲!
Morph!
墨菲  地图在哪!
Morph, where's the map?
开什么玩笑!  还在船上?
Are you serious? It's back on the ship?
让那个水泡安静点  趴下
Stifle that blob and get low.
他们下来了
We've got company.
得找个能防守的地方
We need a more defensible position.
霍金斯先生  去侦察一下
Mr. Hawkins, scout ahead.
是  舰长
Aye, Captain.
Unh!
小心  小心
Steady, steady.
让我来看看
Now, let's have a look at that.
[Morph chattering]
[Gasps]
Shh. Shh.
[Powers up]
- Aah! - Aah!
真是太棒了!
This is fantastic!
终于有一个碳基生物来救我了!
A carbon-based life form come to rescue me at last!
我只想紧紧地抱住你  不要再离开我
I just want to hug you and squeeze you and hold you close to me.
好了  好了  你能放开我吗?
All right. Okay. Would you just let go of me?
噢  抱歉  抱歉
Oh, sorry, sorry, sorry.
只是  我被放逐的太久了
It's just I've been marooned for so long.
当然了  独居也不错  别误会我的意思
I mean, solitude's fun. Don't get me wrong.
不过老天爷  独居个一百年
For heaven's sakes, after a hundred years,
是人都得发疯的!  哈哈哈!
you go a little nuts! Ha, ha, ha!
不好意思  我有点...
I'm sorry. Am I...
我是...呃
l am, um...
我的名字是...呃
My name is, uh...
[Cuckoo Cuckoo]
本  对了  我叫本
B.E.N.! Of course, I'm B.E.N.
生物电子领航员  哦
Bioelectronic Navigator. Oops.
-请问你是  -吉姆
- And you are? - Jim.
哦  很高兴认识你  小吉
Oh, what a pleasure to meet you, Jimmy.
-是吉姆  -随便了
- It's Jim. - Anyway...
听着  我现在很忙  好吗
Look, I'm kind of in a hurry, okay?
我要找一个藏身之处  有海盗在追我
I got to find a place to hide, and there's pirates chasing me.
海盗!  别让我见到海盗!
Pirates! Don't get me started on pirates!
我不喜欢他们  我还记得弗林特船长
I don't like them. I remember Captain Flint.
那家伙脾气可大了
This guy had such a temper.
等等  你认识弗林特船长?
Wait, wait, wait. You knew Captain Flint?
要我说他那是情绪波动症闹的
I think he suffered from mood swings, personally.
当然我也不是心理专家
I'm not a therapist, and anyway,
不过  要是觉得我唠叨你就跟我说
but I... You let me know when I'm rambling.
那就意味着  等等
But that means... But wait.
就是说你知道宝藏的事?
But then you gotta know about the treasure?
-宝藏?  -对  弗林特的宝藏
- Treasure? - Yeah, Flint's trove?
从上千个星球搜刮来的掠夺品
You know, loot of a thousand worlds.
这个嘛...
It's, well...
有点...记忆有点模糊了
lt's all a little... Little... Little fuzzy.
等等  我...我记起来了
Wait. I... I r-r-remember.
真的  我...宝藏!
I do. I... Treasure!
好多宝藏  埋在机械...
Lots of treasure buried in the centroid...
机械构造的核心
Centroid... Centroid of the mechanism.
还有一扇门开了又关...
And there was this big door opening and closing...
开了又关...
and opening and closing...
还有弗林特舰长要确保...
and Captain Flint wanted to make sure...
没有任何人能找到它的宝藏  所以...
nobody could ever get to his treasure...
我就帮他...
So I helped him. [Spluttering]
啊!  数据读取出错!  重启!
Aah! Data inaccessible! Reboot!
本?  本?  本!
B.E.N.? B.E.N.? B.E.N.!
重启!  啊!  你是谁呀?
Reboot! Aah! And you are?
等一下  宝藏怎么了?
Wait, wait, wait! What about the treasure?
你是拉里  对吗
I want to say Larry.
机械装置的核心...还是
The centroid of the mechanism, or...
抱歉  我的记性不如以前了
I'm sorry. My memory isn't what it used to be.
我失忆了
I've lost my mind.
失忆了  你没找到吗?
I've lost my mind. You haven't found it, have you?
我丢失的零件  我的主记忆芯片?
My missing piece? My primary memory circuit?
听着  本  我急着要找到个藏身之处  好吗?
Look, B.E.N., I really need to find a place to hide, okay?
所以我要  先走了
So I'm just gonna be, you know, moving on.
哦  呃...
Oh, uh...
那好吧
So, well, then,
我想这就是道别了  是吧
I guess this is good-bye, huh?
很抱歉  我这么功能紊乱
I'm sorry that I'm so dysfunctional.
那  你走吧  不用管我
So, uh, go ahead and... I do understand.
真的  再见
I do. Bye-bye.
[Whines]
[Sighs]
如果你想要一起来...
Look, if you're gonna come along,
你必须少说话
you're gonna have to stop talking.
太好了!  哈哈哈!
Huzzah! Ha, ha, ha!
噢, 这太棒了!
Oh, this is fantastic!
我和我的好伙计在找一个...
Me and my best buddy out lookin' for a...
[Clears throat]
少说话
[Whispering] Being quiet.
而且你也别再碰我了
And you have to stop touching me.
我不说也不碰  我的两个基本原则
Touching and talking. That's my two big no-nos.
好吧  我想我们应该...
Okay. Now, I think that we should...
好吧  在我们开始搜索之前...
Say, listen, before we go out on our big search...
可以到寒舍停留一下吗
would you mind if we made a quick pit stop at my place? [CHUCKLES]
我有点急
Kind of urgent.
本  我想你正好解决了我的问题
B.E.N., I think you just solved my problem.
不好意思  我这有点乱
Pardon the mess, people.
照理说在这住了100年
You'd think in 100 years
应该有很多时间打扫
I would've dusted a little more often,
但是你知道  一个人住久了
But, you know, when you're batchin' it,
就比较随便了
you tend to let things go.
噢  你们好幸福啊
Aw. Isn't that sweet?
我觉得老式的浪漫非常感人  你觉得呢?
I find old-fashioned romance so touching, don't you?
恩爱的夫妻来喝一杯吧?
How about drinks for the happy couple?
哦  哦  哦  不
Oh, uh, ooh. Uh, no.
谢谢  我们不喝
Thank you, we don't drink,
而且  我们也不是夫妻
and we're not a couple.
Ahem.
你们看这些符号
Look at these markings.
和地图上一摸一样
They're identical to the ones on the map.
我怀疑这是一个古老文明遗留下来的象形文字
I suspect these are the hieroglyphic remnants of an ancient culture.
霍金斯先生
Mr. Hawkins,
不要让人靠近这里  噢!
Stop anyone who tries to approach. Ohh!
好了  好了  你听我说
Yes, yes. Now listen to me,
暂时不要发号施令  好好躺下来休息
Stop giving orders for a few milliseconds and lie still.
很有说服力  博士
Very forceful, Doctor.
继续  再说点别的
Go on. Say something else.
嘿  看呐  那还有你们的同伴
Hey, look! There's some more of your buddies!
嘿  伙计们  我们在这儿!
Hey, fellas! We're over here, fellas!
Oh! Uhh! Ooh! Ohh!
别浪费你们的子弹了
Stop wastin' your fire!
上面的人  你们好吗?
Hello, up there!
吉姆?
Jimbo?
舰长还好吗?
If it's all right with the captain.
我想跟你聊聊
I'd like a short word with ya.
不耍花样  只是聊聊
No tricks, just a little palaver.
他是为地图来讨价还价的
Come to bargain for the map, doubtless.
该死!
Pestilential...
-啊!  -舰长
- Ugh! - Captain.
也就是说  他以为地图还在我们手上
That means that he thinks we still have it.
墨菲!  我正想你跑哪儿去了呢
Morphy! I wondered where you lit off to.
[Groaning]
Ooh.
自从我们在伙房里打了一架...
Oh, this poor old leg's downright snarky...
这条腿就彻底不管用了
since that game attack we had in the galley. [Chuckles]
Ahh.
无论你在那里听到了什么
Whatever you heard back there,
至少关于你的那些话...
at least the part concerning you...
我真的不是那个意思
I didn't mean a word of it.
要是让那些穷凶极恶的家伙认定我心软了...
If that bloodthirsty lot had thought I'd gone soft...
他们会把我们都宰了的
they'd have gutted us both.
听我说  如果我们见机行事...
Listen to me. If we play our cards right...
我们可以安全的离开这里  享受荣华富贵
we can both walk away from this rich as kings.
是吗?
- Yeah? [Chuckles]
只要你把地图给我...然后
You get me that map and...
一部分的的宝藏就归你
an even portion of the treasure is yours.
伙计
Boy.
你可真有一套
You are really something.
说什么我有天赋啦...
All that talk of greatness
什么辉煌的荣耀...  真是可笑
light coming off my sails, what a joke.
听我说  吉姆
Now, just see here, Jimbo...
不过  至少你教对了我一件事...坚持到底  对吧
I mean, at least you taught me one thing. Stick to it, right?
这正是我要做的
Well, that's just what I'm gonna do.
我一定会让你永远也看不到一丁点  我的宝藏!
I'm gonna make sure that you never see one drabloon of my treasure!
那些财宝都是我的!!
That treasure is owed me, by thunder!
那你就别用我的地图  看你能不能找到
Well, try to find it without my map, by thunder!
噢  你还是没学会挑对手是吗  小子
Oh, you still don't know how to pick your fights, do you, boy?
你给我听着
Now, mark me.
如果明天天亮前我还没拿到地图
Either I get that map by dawn tomorrow,
你也不肯帮我  我就用船上的大炮
or so help me, I'll use the ship's cannons
把你们全都炸上天!
to blast ya all to kingdom come!
墨菲  跟我走
Morph, hop to it.
快!
Now!
该死!
Oh, blast it!
先生们...
Gentlemen...
我们必须呆在一起...
we must stay together and...
并且...
And...
-噢  -并且什么...什么
- Ohh. - And What? What?
我们必须呆在一起  还有呢?
We must stay together and what?
博士  你的眼睛真的很漂亮
Doctor, you have wonderful eyes.
她已经神志不清了!
She's lost her mind!
你赶紧帮帮她
Well, you gotta help her.
该死的  吉姆  我是天文学博士  不是医学博士
Dang it, Jim. I'm an astronomer, not a doctor.
我是说  我是个博士  不是个医生
I mean, I am a doctor, but I'm not that kind of doctor.
我有博士学位  但那是两回事
I have a doctorate. It's not the same thing.
博士学位救不了人命
You can't help people with a doctorate.
我只能眼睁睁看着  束手无策
You just sit there, and you're useless.
没事的  博士
It's okay, Doc.
会没事的
It's all right.
是啊  博士  吉姆知道怎么让我们离开这里
Yeah, Doc! Jimmy knows exactly how to get out of this.
吉姆对这些事儿可在行了
It's just Jimmy has this knowledge of things.
吉姆  有什么主意吗?
Jim, any thoughts at all?
没有地图  我们死定了
Without the map, we're dead.
我们想逃跑  也死定了
If we try to leave, we're dead.
-可如果继续呆在这...  -"我们死定了"
- If we stay here... -"We're dead!
"死定了!  死定了!  死定了!"
"We're dead! We're dead!"
我觉得吉姆可能要一个人安静的想一想
Well, I think that Jimmy could use a little quiet time. Heh.
我就先从后门溜了
So I'll just slip out the back door.
-后门?  -对
- Back door? - Oh, yeah.
凉风可以从这个地方吹进来...
I get this delightful breeze through here...
我觉得这很重要  因为室内要多通风啊...
which I think is important, because ventilation among friends...
哇  这都是什么呀?
Whoa. What is all this stuff?
你是说横穿这个星球绵延几英里...
You mean the miles and miles of machinery that run...
不停运转的这些机器设备吗?
through the entire course of the inside of this planet?
我也不知道
Not a clue.
嘿  博士  我想我找到出路了!
Hey, Doc! Doc! I think I found a way out of here!
不不  等等吉姆  舰长让我们呆在一起...
No, no. Jim, wait. The captain ordered us to stay...
-我马上回来  -深水炸弹!
- I'll be back. - Cannonball!
Woof.
[Snoring]
-有什么计划?  -嘘...本  小声点
- So, what's the plan? - Shh. B.E.N., quiet.
好了  我们出来了
[Whispering] Okay, here it is.
我们潜回船上去  破坏激光炮
We sneak back to the Legacy, disable the laser cannons,
拿回地图
and bring back the map.
真是好主意
That's a good plan.
我喜欢  可唯一的问题是...
I like that plan. The only thing is...
我们怎么上去啊?
I'm wondering, how do we get there?
用那个
On that.
-啊  -本!  嘘!
- Aah! - B.E.N., Shh!
抱歉  抱歉  抱歉
Sorry, sorry. Sorry.
我去那地图  你待在这
Okay, I'll get the map. You wait here.
遵命  吉姆  我负责毁坏激光炮!
Roger, Jimmy. I'll neutralize laser cannons, sir!
本!  本!
B.E.N.! B.E.N.!
哟呼  哟呼  海盗滴生活...
Yo-ho, yo-ho, a pirate's life for me
[Humming] [Sighs]
不就是毁掉大炮嘛  有什么难的?
Disable a few laser cannons. What is the big deal?
我要做的就是找出那根电线然后...
All we gotta do is find that one little wire.
[Gasps]
我的妈呀
Oh, mama.
[Sighs]
找到了!
- Yes. [Alarm Blaring]
搞错了
Bad, B.E.N. Bad.
插回去
Okay, fixing.
那个愚蠢的机器人会让我们都...
That stupid robot's gonna get us all...
送命的
Killed.
伙房的小子
Cabin boy.
[Gasps]
[Growling]
[Squealing]
[Powers Up]
哦  别紧张
Whoops. Okay, don't panic.
吸气  呼气...
Breathing in, breathing out...
- Aah! - Hmm?
[Poink] Raah!
这一定是大炮那根线
This has gotta be cannons.
看来不是
Maybe not.
[Grunting]
Heh, heh.
过来  过来  过来
Come on, come on, come on
不!
No!
哦  好极了
Oh, yes.
替我向埃柔先生问好
Do say hello to Mr. Arrow.
[Gasps]
你自己跟他说吧!
Tell him yourself!
Aah!
给我回去  你这淘气的插头!  噢!
Back you go, you naughty plug! Oh!
[Grunts]
[Panting]
[Ratting]
[Coughing]
墨菲?
- Morph? [Chatters]
激光炮已经失效了
Laser cannons disconnected
吉姆舰长
Captain Jimmy, sir!
轻松搞定
Gee, that wasn't so tough.
博士  博士快醒醒!
Doc! Doc, wake up!
我拿到地图了
I got the map.
干得好  吉姆  干得漂亮
Fine work, Jimbo. Fine work indeed.
谢谢你给我们指路
Thanks for showing us the way, boy.
Aah!
这个铁疙瘩是什么?
What's this sorry stack of metal?
别碰我的脸!
Not the face!
你和我一样  吉姆
You're just like me, Jimbo
你讨厌失败
Ya hates to lose.
[Chuckles]
什么鬼...
What the devil's the...
打开!
Open it.
我要动手了
I'd get busy.
[Crew murmuring]
看到没  多么神奇啊
Oh, the powers that be. Would you look?
Ha ha ha ha!
把他们绑在一起  等我们回来再...什么?
Tie him up and leave him with the others till we... What?
想要地图的话
You want the map,
就带我一块去
you're taking me, too.
[Groans]
Hmm.
[Chuckles]
我们把他们都带上
We'll take 'em all.
Unh.
[Chattering]
没事  墨菲  没事的
It's okay, Morph. It's okay.
吉姆  我不知道你怎么样...
Jimmy, I don't know about you...
但是我开始看到我的一生在眼前闪过
but I'm starting to see my life pass in front of my eyes.
至少  我想这是我的生活
At least, I think it's my life.
我和一个叫着卢皮的机器人跳过舞吗?
Was I ever dancing with an android named Lupe?
本!  嘘...
B.E.N., shh.
事情还不算完
This isn't over yet.
我们就要到了  伙计们
We're gettin' close, lads.
我闻到宝藏的味道了
I smell treasure a-waitin'.
Huh?
宝藏在哪?
Where is it?
我什么都没看到  什么都没有!
I see nothing! One great, big stinking hunk of nothing!
怎么回事  吉姆?
What's going on, Jimbo?
我不知道  我打不开了
I don't know. I can't get it open.
我就知道  我们不该跟着这个小子
We should've never followed this boy!
Hey!
我劝你快点把它给弄好  快!
I'd suggest you get that gizmo going again, and fast!
把他杀了  剖开他的肚子!
Let's rip his gizzard right out, right now!
把他扔下去!
Throw him off the cliff!
[Rumbing]
我的天呐
Oh, have mercy.
礁湖星云?
The Lagoon Nebula?
离这儿隔了半个银河系呢
But that's halfway across the galaxy.
一扇大门...
A big door
开开关关
opening and closing.
我看看
Let's see.
金纳皮斯
Kinapis.
蒙特里莎太空港
Montressor spaceport.
原来弗林特就这样...
So that's how Flint did it.
靠这个传送门  在宇宙里四处遨游  强取豪夺
He used this portal to roam the universe, stealing treasure.
可他把财宝藏在哪了?
But where'd he stash it all?
那该死的财宝在哪里?
Where's that blasted treasure?
宝藏!  宝藏!
Treasure! Treasure!
埋藏在...
It's buried in the...
埋藏在机械装置的核心
Buried in the centroid of the mechanism.
如果这整个星球就是一个机械装置...
What if the whole planet is the mechanism...
那宝藏就该埋在这个星球的核心!
and the treasure is buried in the center of this planet?
我们要怎么样到星球的核心去呢?
And how in blue blazes are we supposed to get there?
只要开启对应的门
Just open the right door.
[Alarm Beeping]
等等我!  等等我!
Wait for me! Wait for me!
[Gasps]
[Cheering]
上千个星球的财宝!
The loot of a thousand worlds.
我们需要一艘更大的船!
We are going to need a bigger boat!
[Laughing]
这一切看起来都是那么的熟悉
This is all seeming very familiar.
为什么我记不起来
I can't remember why.
本  到这边来
B.E.N., come on.
我们离开这里  但不能空手离开
We're getting out of here, and we're not leaving empty-handed.
可是  可是  吉姆...吉姆!
But... But, Jimmy! Jimmy!
我花了一辈子的时间
A lifetime of searching.
终于...
And at long last...
找到了
I can touch it.
你没觉得奇怪吗?
Do you know what's strange?
我无法告诉你这有多令人沮丧  吉姆
I can't tell you how frustrating this is, Jimmy,
因为有些东西
'cause there's something just...
在我的脑子里盘旋不去
It's nagging at the back of my mind.
Aah!
-弗林特船长  -就是他!
- Captain Flint? - In the flesh!
呃...只是皮肤、内脏...
Well, sort of, except for skin, organs,
还其他那肌肉...
or anything that, that... That resembles flesh,
都不在了
that's not there.
我还是觉得有点奇怪你知道吗?
And yet it's so odd, you know?
我记得有什么可怕的事
I remember there was something horrible
弗林特不想任何人知道...
Flint didn't want anyone else to know...
但我就是想不起来了
but I just can't remember what it was.
噢  丧失记忆真是太惨了!
Oh, a mind is a terrible thing to lose!
[Sobbing]
本  我想我找到你的记忆了
B.E.N., I think I just found your mind.
-别动!  -啊!
- Hold still. - Aah!
吉姆  你的手好凉  好凉啊
Jimmy, your hands are very, very cold.
Whoa!
你好
Hello.
吉姆  我刚刚在想
You know, Jimmy, I was just thinking
我刚刚在想...
I was just think...
全都回来了  我所有的记忆!
It's all flooding back! All my memories!
弗林特拆掉了我的主记忆芯片...
Right up until Flint pulled my memory circuits...
那样我就不会告诉别人他设下的陷阱!
so I could never tell anybody about his booby trap!
[Crashing]
-说到陷阱...  -什么?
- Speaking of which... - Huh?
弗林特想要确保...
Flint wanted to make sure...
没人能偷走他的宝藏
that nobody could ever steal his treasure,
他在整个星球上都装了炸药
so he rigged this whole planet
会把你炸的比风筝还高!
to blow higher than a Kalepsian kite!
快跑  吉姆  快逃命吧!
Run, Jimmy! Run for your life!
你回去帮船长和博士
You go back and help the captain and Doc!
如果我5分钟后还没回去  你们就先走
If I'm not there in 5 minutes, leave without me.
我绝不会留下我的朋友  吉姆
I am not leaving my buddy Jimmy.
除非他那样看着我
Unless he looks at me like that.
待会见  吉姆
Bye, Jim!
不！  不！  噢！  不！  噢！  不！
No! No! Oh, no! Oh, no!
不!
No!
Aah!
快回来  你们这些笨蛋!
Come back here, ya blighters!
[Rumbling]
我这一生  都在梦想这样的冒险经历
All my life, I dreamed of an adventure like this.
[Sighs]
抱歉
I'm just sorry
我没能给你帮上什么忙
I couldn't have been more helpful to you.
哦  别傻了
Oh, don't be daft.
你已经帮了我很多  真的
You've been very helpful. Truly.
我觉得我就是没一丁点儿用的弱者
I feel like such a useless weakling
手腕还很细
with abnormally thin wrists.
打搅一下  粗野的海盗
Excuse me, brutish pirate.
[Belches]
就是你  我有一个问题
Yes, you. I have a question.
是你的身体对你的脑袋来说太大了呢?
Is it that your body is too massive for your teeny-tiny head,
还是对你肥大的身躯来说你的脑袋太小了呢?
or is it that your head is too teeny-tiny for your big, fat body?
信不信我揍你!
I pummel you good!
是的  我相信  在在那之前...
Yes, I'm sure you will, but before you do...
我还有最后一个问题  这是你的吗?
I have one more question. Is this yours?
Uhh...
太好了!  墨菲  我们就要离开这了
Yes! Morph, we are so out of here!
[Cackling]
啊  吉姆!
Ah, Jimbo!
你真是这宇宙的第七大奇迹呀!
Aren't you the seventh wonder of the universe?
退后!
Get back!
我喜欢你  孩子  我费了这么大劲...
I like you, lad, but I've come too far
不能让你妨碍我得到宝藏
to let you stand between me and me treasure.
Aah!
不...休想!
Oh, no, you don't!
[Chattering]
什么?
What?
吉姆
Jimbo.
伸过来!
Reach for me now!
抓住我!
Reach!
我...
I...
我够不着!
I can't!
我...
I...
[Sighs]
哦  我真是个笨蛋!
Oh, blast me for a fool!
[Yells]
[Groans]
席尔瓦  你放弃了宝藏?
Silver, you gave UP?
它困扰了我一生  我已经想通了
Just a lifelong obsession, Jim. I'll get over it.
嘿  吉姆!
Aloha, Jimmy!
快点!  还有2分34秒
Hurry, people! We got exactly two minutes
这个星球就要爆炸了!
and 34 seconds till planet's destruction!
你做得很好  博士
You're doing fine, Doctor.
现在慢慢打方向  慢一点!
Now ease her over gently... Gently!
Aah!
我们真不应该来这会爆炸星球探险!
We were better off on exploding planet!
把我们送出去  金属人!
Take us out of here, metal man!
遵命  舰长!
Ave, Captain!
舰长  你可真是关键时刻从天而...
Captain, you dropped from the heavens in the nick of...
这些话留给法官说吧  席尔瓦!
Save your claptrap for the judge, Silver!
[Chuckles]
喷射器尾部受损  舰长!
Mizzen sail demobilized, Captain!
推进器只剩30％的能量
Thrusters at only 30% of capacity.
30%?  那意味着...
30%? That means we're...
我们不能及时逃离这爆炸了
We'll never clear the planet's explosion in time.
-我们要掉头回去!  -什么?
- We gotta turn around. - What?
那有个传送门  我们可以从那离开!
There's a portal back there. It can get us out of here!
但是吉姆  那个传送门不是通往一片火海吗?
Pardon me, Jim, but didn't that portal open onto a raging inferno?
没错  不过我要改变它
Yes, but I'm gonna change that.
我要开启另一扇门
I'm gonna open a different door.
舰长  真的  我不知道这怎么可能
Captain, really, I don't see how this is possible...
就听他的!
Listen to the boy!
还有1分29秒  这个星球就要毁灭了!
One minute, 29 seconds till planet's destruction!
-吉姆  你要怎么做  -只要把这个接上去
- What do you need, Jim? - Just some way to attach this.
好的  后退  后退!
All right. Stand back. Stand back, now.
好了
There you go.
"好了"
"There you go."
好的  现在无论发生什么
Okay. Now, no matter what happens,
让这艘船秉直朝传送门开过去
keep the ship heading straight for that portal.
还剩58秒!
Fifty-eight seconds!
听到他的话了吗?
Well, you heard him!
快让这该死的船掉头!
Get this blasted heap turned 'round!
博士  把船头对准传送门
Doctor, head us back to the portal.
遵命  舰长
Aye, Captain.
往右转  往右!
Go to the right! The right!
我知道  我知道  你能让我自己驾驶吗?!
I know, I know! Will you just let me drive?
25秒!
Twenty-five seconds!
不!  不!
No! No!
加油  小子
Come on, lad.
17秒!
Seventeen seconds!
Seven...
6  5  4
six, five, four...
3  2
three, two...
Wow! Yeah!
你成功了  吉姆!
You done it, Jimmy!
你成功了  孩子!  哈哈哈!
You done it, boy! Ha, ha, ha!
我就说过这小伙子有天赋!
Didn't I say the lad had greatness in him?
[Cheering]
不太正统  但是却很有用
Unorthodox, but ludicrously effective.
我很乐意推荐你...
I'd be proud to recommend you
去星际学院  他们会用得着像你这样的人才
to the interstellar academy. They could use a man like you.
等着吧  你妈妈听到这个一定很高兴!
Just wait until your mother hears about this!
出生入死那些情节就省了
Of course, we may downplay the life-threatening parts.
吉姆  这真是难忘的经历!
Jimmy, that was unforgettable!
我知道你不喜欢让我碰你  但是...
I know you don't like touching...
准备好迎接一个大大的拥抱吧  我要抱你啦!
but get ready for a hug, big guy, 'cause I gotta hug ya!
Ha ha ha ha!
嘿  你回抱我了
Hey, you hugged me back.
我跟自己保证过不会哭的
Oh, I promised myself I wouldn't cry.
[Sobbing]
有谁带纸巾了吗?
Does anyone have a tissue?
[Morph squeaking]
-墨菲  我们得快点离开  -我知道
- Morphy, we gotta make tracks. - I know.
你从来不服输  对吗
You never quit, do you?
啊  吉姆  哈哈!
Ah, Jimbo! Ha ha!
我只是在检查  确保...
I was merely checking to make sure
我们的大艇拴牢了
our last longboat was safe and secure.
Mmm.
呣...
Well,
这样就牢了
that should hold it.
我把你教的太好了
I taught you too well.
如果你放我们一马  我们就不用去蹲大牢了
If you don't mind, we'd just as soon avoid prison.
小墨菲它自由惯了
Little Morphy here, he's a free spirit.
被关在牢笼里  它会伤心的
Being in a cage, it'd break his heart.
Oh!
和我们一起走怎么样  小伙子
What say you ship out with us, lad?
你和我  霍金斯和席尔瓦
You and me, Hawkins and Silver,
自由自在  不被任何人束缚!
full of ourselves and no ties to anyone!
知道吗  在我刚上船的时候...
You know, when I got on this boat...
我可能会毫不犹豫地接受你的邀请
I would've taken you up on that offer in a second,
但是...我遇到这个老半机械人...
but, uh, I met this old cyborg...
他教过我要开辟自己的航线
and he taught me that I could chart my own course.
那正是我要做的
That's what I'm gonna do.
那么你在你的船头看见了什么?
And what do you see off that bow of yours?
我的未来
A future.
[Chuckles]
好啊...
why...
看看你  就像太阳一般闪耀
look at ya, glowing like a solar fire.
你和别人不一样  吉姆
You're something special, Jim.
你一定会干出一番惊天动地的大事来的!
You're gonna rattle the stars, you are.
[Clears throat]
我的机器眼又漏油了
Got a bit of grease in this cyborg eye of mine.
[Sniffles]
[Sobbing]
哦  嘿  墨菲  我们还会再见的  好吗?
Oh, hey, Morph. I'll see ya around, okay?
"回头见"
"See ya around."
墨菲  我给你安排个工作
Morphy, I got a job for ya.
你给我好好盯着这个小子
I need you to keep an eye on this here pup.
你愿意帮我这个忙吗?
Will ya do me that little favor?
遵命  船长
Aye-aye, Captain.
噢  还有一件事
Oh, and one more thing.
这是给你妈妈的...
This is for your dear mother...
用来重建她的旅馆
to rebuild that inn of hers.
别再惹麻烦了  老家伙
Stay out of trouble, ya old scalawag.
为什么这么说
[Laughs] Why, Jimbo, lad,
我什么时候惹麻烦了?
when have I ever done otherwise?
[Laughing]
[Cheering]
[Yawns]
[All gasp]
[All Cheer]
[Playing Music]
[Crying]
[Laughing]
♪ It's good to see the sun And feel this place
♪ This place I never thought Would feel like home
♪ And I ran forever
♪ Far away
♪ And I always thought I'd end up here alone
♪ Somehow The world has changed
♪ And I've come home
♪ To give you back the things They took from you
♪ And I feel you now
♪ I'm not alone
♪ I always know Where you are
♪ When I see myself
♪ Where you are
♪ And I found something That was always there
♪ Sometimes it's got to hurt Before you feel
♪ But now I'm strong And I won't kneel
♪ Except to thank Who's watching over me
♪ And somehow I feel so strong
♪ And I've begun To be the one
♪ I never thought I'd be
♪ And I feel you now
♪ I'm not alone
♪ I always know Where you are
♪ And When I See Myself
♪ Where you are
♪ Now it's all so clear
♪ And I believe
♪ That everything's been Opened up to me
♪ And I feel you now
♪ I'm not alone
♪ I always know
♪ I always know Where you are
♪ And when I see myself
♪ And when I feel the sun
♪ I always know Where you are
♪ And when I see myself
♪ Where you are
[Instrumental Music Playing]